<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: github | Chandrahasa]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/categories/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-13T02:49:12-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chandra]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crazydomains - crazy issues]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/2013/07/09/crazydomains-crazy-issues/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-09T06:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/2013/07/09/crazydomains-crazy-issues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I purchased domain name from crazydomains, mainly to host my blog, because the domain name was cheaper at crazydomains. But little did I know that I will not be able to update my DNS records, unless I pay more for it. Creating a CNAME record seem to be pretty basic service, but alas crazydomains will not give you. Now I know why they named themselves as crazydomains.</p>

<p>Now let us look at what needs to be done for custom domain setup.</p>

<ol>
<li>Create a CNAME file under source folder :
<code>
echo 'your-domain.com' &gt;&gt; source/CNAME
</code></li>
<li>Create a CNAME record for sub-domains (A record for domain) under DNS settings.

<blockquote><p>Ref: <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/github/#custom_domains">Deploying to Github Pages</a></p></blockquote></li>
</ol>


<p>Now, since I could not create CNAME, I was looking for other options. Luckily there are some options available, like:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freedns.afraid.org/">FreeDNS</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cloudns.net/">ClouDNS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Of the above I have tried only Cloudflare. Cloudflare basically a website optimizer mainly routes the traffic via their network. So, its double benefit.</p>

<ul>
<li>Create an account in Cloudflare</li>
<li>Once you login, you will have to add your domain name.</li>
<li>It will scan your DNS settings, adds all the missing records if any (like for www etc)</li>
<li>Now add a new CNAME as follows:
<code>&lt;your sub-domain name&gt;</code> and its alias name, which is <code>&lt;github user&gt;.github.io</code> as shown below.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/cloudflare-dns_settings.jpg" width="650" height="350" title="&lsquo;image&rsquo; &lsquo;images&rsquo;" ></p>

<ul>
<li>Once done, click on <em>I&rsquo;m done entering my DNS Records</em>.</li>
<li>Now Cloudflare will provide you two nameservers (it could be different for different accounts)</li>
</ul>


<p>Now login to crazydomains,</p>

<ul>
<li>Click on Domains and click <em>Update Name Servers</em> under DNS settings.</li>
<li>Delete the existing crazy domains name servers and enter the two nameservers given by cloudflare as follows:.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/crazydomain-dns_settings.jpg" width="650" height="350" title="&lsquo;image&rsquo; &lsquo;images&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it. It may take an 10 &ndash; 20 minutes. Now you can go to your subdomain and see that its pulling content off your github page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Github Hosted Blog with Octopress in Cloud9]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/2013/06/19/github-hosted-blog-with-octopress-in-cloud9/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T06:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/2013/06/19/github-hosted-blog-with-octopress-in-cloud9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was looking for blogging framework, there were many choices like <a href="http://tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a>, <a href="http://wordpress.com">Wordpress</a> etc. But when I came across Octopress, I really liked it. I can just write posts in markdown syntax and host it easily in Github.</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>  is a blogging framework for Jekyl, which isa static site generator powering Github Pages.</p></blockquote>

<p>Writing blog using Octopress and hosting it in Github Pages, requires the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Ruby 1.9.3</li>
<li>Git &ndash; a distributed version control system</li>
<li>Account in <a href="https://github.com">Github</a></li>
</ul>


<p>But having these environment in my local system was not an option, as I wanted to blog from anywhere. This is where Cloud9 helped me.</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9</a> is an online IDE where Ruby, Git are pre-installed.</p></blockquote>

<p>So, once you sign up for an account with Cloud 9, all you need is to create an workspace. In free edition, you can have one private workspace.</p>

<p>Now, go to your workspace, and follow the steps as outlined below in the terminal window
<code>
git clone git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git myblog
</code></p>

<blockquote><p>This creates a directory called myblog and copies all the related data from octopress.</p></blockquote>

<p>Now goto the octopress directory and issue the following commands
<code>
cd myblog
bundle install
rake install
</code></p>

<blockquote><p>This will install the default theme. Check _config.yml and update all details like blog name, blog address, twitter id, disqus id etc</p></blockquote>

<p>Next step is to generate the blog and preview it.
<code>
rake generate
rake preview
</code></p>

<p>Preview within Cloud9 may result in  Permission denied &ndash; bind(2) (Errno::EACCES). To resolve this issue, edit RakeFile and modify the following
```
&hellip;.                                                                                                                                                                               <br/>
&hellip;.</p>

<h1>server_port     = &ldquo;4000&rdquo;      # port for preview server eg. localhost:4000</h1>

<p>server_host     = ENV[&lsquo;IP&rsquo;] ||= &lsquo;0.0.0.0&rsquo;     # server bind address for preview server                                                                                             <br/>
server_port     = ENV[&lsquo;PORT&rsquo;] ||= &ldquo;4000&rdquo;      # port for preview server eg. localhost:4000                                                                                         <br/>
&hellip;.                                                                                                                                                                               <br/>
&hellip;.</p>

<h1>rackupPid = Process.spawn(&ldquo;rackup &mdash;port #{server_port}&rdquo;)</h1>

<p>rackupPid = Process.spawn(&ldquo;rackup &mdash;host #{server_host} &mdash;port #{server_port}&rdquo;)                                                                                                    <br/>
```</p>

<blockquote><p>Refer [<a href="http://www.devopsy.com/blog/2012/10/04/octopress-on-cloud9/">http://www.devopsy.com/blog/2012/10/04/octopress-on-cloud9/</a>] for more details</p></blockquote>

<p>Now you can preview your blog on <code>&lt;blog_name&gt;.&lt;cloud 9 username&gt;.c9.io</code></p>

<h3>Deploying to Github pages</h3>

<p>Login to github.com and create a repo as <username>.github.io.
Now on your cloud9 workspace, invoke
<code>
cd myblog
rake setup_github_pages
</code></p>

<p>Enter repo url as:<code>git@github.com:&lt;github username&gt;/&lt;github username&gt;.github.io</code></p>

<blockquote><p>Note: Make sure to add cloud9 ssh key into github. Cloud9 ssh key is avilable at your account settings, copy this ssh key and add it in Github account settings.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Now generate the blog and deploy to github</h3>

<p><code>
rake generate
rake deploy
</code>
Now you are done with deploying your blog onto Github and you can go to your blog at <code>http://&lt;github username&gt;.github.io</code>.</p>

<h3>Commit the source</h3>

<p>Now commit the source so that you don&rsquo;t loose any of the setup files and can checkout the code in someother system and start blogging.
<code>
git add .                                                                                                                                                                            
git commit -m 'your message'                                                                        
git push origin source                                                                                                                                                               
</code></p>

<h3>Creating new post</h3>

<p><code>                                                                                                                                                                                 
rake new_post["My new blog"]                                                                                                                                                         
</code>
This will generate a file in the source_posts folder which you can edit.</p>

<p>To generate your blog and deploy it, follow the same steps as outlined above.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
