<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cloudfare | Chandrahasa]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/categories/cloudfare/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-24T06:45:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chandra]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crazydomains - crazy issues]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/2013/07/09/crazydomains-crazy-issues/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-09T06:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.kchandrahasa.com/blog/2013/07/09/crazydomains-crazy-issues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I purchased domain name from crazydomains, mainly to host my blog, because the domain name was cheaper at crazydomains. But little did I know that I will not be able to update my DNS records, unless I pay more for it. Creating a CNAME record seem to be pretty basic service, but alas crazydomains will not give you. Now I know why they named themselves as crazydomains.</p>

<p>Now let us look at what needs to be done for custom domain setup.</p>

<!--more-->


<ol>
<li>Create a CNAME file under source folder :
<code>
echo 'your-domain.com' &gt;&gt; source/CNAME
</code></li>
<li>Create a CNAME record for sub-domains (A record for domain) under DNS settings.

<blockquote><p>Ref: <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/github/#custom_domains">Deploying to Github Pages</a></p></blockquote></li>
</ol>


<p>Now, since I could not create CNAME, I was looking for other options. Luckily there are some options available, like:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freedns.afraid.org/">FreeDNS</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cloudns.net/">ClouDNS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Of the above I have tried only Cloudflare. Cloudflare basically a website optimizer mainly routes the traffic via their network. So, its double benefit.</p>

<ul>
<li>Create an account in Cloudflare</li>
<li>Once you login, you will have to add your domain name.</li>
<li>It will scan your DNS settings, adds all the missing records if any (like for www etc)</li>
<li>Now add a new CNAME as follows:
<code>&lt;your sub-domain name&gt;</code> and its alias name, which is <code>&lt;github user&gt;.github.io</code> as shown below.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/cloudflare-dns_settings.jpg" width="650" height="350" title="&lsquo;image&rsquo; &lsquo;images&rsquo;" ></p>

<ul>
<li>Once done, click on <em>I&rsquo;m done entering my DNS Records</em>.</li>
<li>Now Cloudflare will provide you two nameservers (it could be different for different accounts)</li>
</ul>


<p>Now login to crazydomains,</p>

<ul>
<li>Click on Domains and click <em>Update Name Servers</em> under DNS settings.</li>
<li>Delete the existing crazy domains name servers and enter the two nameservers given by cloudflare as follows:.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/crazydomain-dns_settings.jpg" width="650" height="350" title="&lsquo;image&rsquo; &lsquo;images&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it. It may take an 10 &ndash; 20 minutes. Now you can go to your subdomain and see that its pulling content off your github page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
